It's a whole new west.
Wild Wild West is a action, adventure, comedy film directed by Barry Sonnenfeld.
Legless Southern inventor Dr.
Arliss Loveless plans to rekindle the Civil War by
assassinating President Ulysses S.
Only two men can stop him: gunfighter James West and
master-of-disguise and inventor Artemus Gordon.
The two must team up to thwart Loveless' plans.
Capt. James West, played by Will Smith.
U.S. Marshal Artemus Gordon / President Grant, played by Kevin Kline.
Dr. Arliss Loveless, played by Kenneth Branagh.
Rita Escobar, played by Salma Hayek Pinault.
Coleman, played by M. Emmet Walsh.
General 'Bloodbath' McGrath, played by Ted Levine.
Wild Wild West is a 1999 American steampunk Western comedy film
directed by Barry Sonnenfeld and written by S.
Wilson and Brent Maddock alongside Jeffrey Price and Peter S.
Seaman, based on a story conceived by Jim and John Thomas.
Loosely adapted from The Wild Wild West, a 1960s television series created by Michael Garrison, it is the
only production in the franchise since the television film More Wild Wild West (1980).
The film stars Will Smith (who previously collaborated with Sonnenfeld on Men
in Black two years earlier in 1997) and Kevin Kline as two U.S.
Secret Service agents who work together to protect U.S.
President Ulysses S.
Grant (Kline in a dual role) and the United States from all manner
of dangerous threats during the American Old West.
The film features a supporting cast consisting of Kenneth Branagh, Salma Hayek and Ted Levine, as well as an orchestral film score
by Western film score veteran Elmer Bernstein and extensive visual effects courtesy of Industrial Light & Magic.
Released theatrically in the United States on June 30, 1999 by Warner Bros.
and produced on a $170 million budget (making it one of the most expensive films ever made when adjusting for inflation at the time of its release), Wild Wild
West was a commercial failure, grossing only $113.8 million domestically and $108.3 million overseas for a worldwide total of $222.1 million.
Receiving mixed-to-negative reviews from critics, the film was nominated for eight Razzies and won five at the 20th Golden
Raspberry Awards, including Worst Picture and Worst Original Song (for the song "Wild Wild West" by Smith).
The film explores themes of inventor, remake, steampunk, cowboy, impersonation.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.